# J Rob Gant

26 Glenwood Rd #1 Somerville, MA 02145

+1 508 345 8013

rgant@alum.wpi.edu

https://rob.gant.ninja/

#### SUMMARY

Senior staff development team lead with 22 years experience building web application software and guiding startup development teams.

High standards and clear communication are essential for building successful startup software teams. Startups experience rapid growth, requiring constant pivoting, feature additions, modifications, and code refactoring. A solid technology stack foundation enables smooth handling of these changes. I believe this is achieved through automated processes for deployment, testing, and linters/static analysis tools in development; combined with clear documentation, code reviews, and shared standards, to help the team grow together effectively on the same path.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Technical Advisor, Stealth Startup**

Boston, MA -- 2024-Present

I am currently working with prospective founders to map out the technology requirements for implementing their fintech product ideas. My focus is on providing insight on how to best structure the team and tools to enable rapid growth and scalability. I have developed technical roadmaps for investor presentations, and assisted the founders in fully understanding the financial PaaS tools necessary for getting a MVP launched. Developed proof of concept websites and applications to demonstrate proposed functionality and flow to investors. This company is currently on re-evaluating their prospects and is on hiatus.

### **Product Manager, Pathfinder Studios**

Remote -- 2024-Present

I joined a contract team consisting of only developers to help them develop the processes necessary for a maturing product. I worked with internal teams, product user stakeholders and end user clients to address communication concerns and documentation deficiencies. I implemented processes for documenting bug reports, feature requests, product roadmap planning, and task prioritization. Developed tools to assist with importation of new data and generating reports for senior stakeholders. This has allowed the product stakeholders to take over primary management of the project and bring it in house.

## Staff Software Engineer, LearnLux, Inc.

Boston, MA -- 2018-2024

Joining as their first full time engineer I converted a contractor-built AngularJS Firebase application to modern Angular with TypeScript. Introduced robust documentation, coding, and unit testing standards using strict linting and minimum 85% unit test coverage. Worked to transition the product from consumer focused to an employer financial wellness benefit. Built a scalable infrastructure as code system using Terraform to ensure that both AWS based front-end and GCP Firebase back-ends were scalable and manageable by a small team. Additionally I lead the initiative to meet SOC 2 compliance and periodic security testing necessary for growth in the industry. Thanks to my early preparation the process was able to be completed without issue during the first six month audit. I provided senior staff with reports and repeatable analysis tools to create presentations for the board of investors quarterly meetings.

I managed development team hiring to grow the team to six software engineers over the course of 3 years. Provided mentoring and training for three junior engineers and assisted two senior engineers with developing processes for a fast paced and growing team.

# Software Engineer, Sober Grid, Inc.

Boston, MA -- 2017-2018

Implemented tools for NSF and NHS grant research projects. I developed a Ruby on Rails based tool that allows researchers to filter Sober Grid users to produce an anonymized cohort for study and targeting. These tools can also be used by the Sober Grid team to target our users for specific content to help prevent relapse. I also set up a Python Anaconda Docker container that our data scientist uses to develop predictive analytics to help develop intervention methods to keep our users sober.

### Chief Technology Officer, sixQ Software

Boston, MA -- 2017

Implemented Angular 4 web app using Angular/cli backed by a Python API framework using role-based access control for a multi-tenancy database design. Unfortunately, as happens in the startup world, this company experienced issues between founders and was closed down in less than a year.

### Senior Software Engineer, True Impact, Inc.

Boston, MA -- 2016-2017

My first project was to design and implement an API in Python with automated test coverage. Using the JSONAPI spec to define the API envelope, I designed the API and documented it using the OpenAPI Specification (Swagger). For the stack I used Docker for scalability and Python Flask for rapid development with decent performance. Pytest and Pylint ensured that the code was tested and well formed. As another major component in this project, I designed a database modeled after the API using Python SQLAlchemy and PyMySQL. I migrated the existing on premise database to a new database hosted in Amazon Relational Database Service for improved scalability and performance.

After completing the API upgrade, our focus moved to updating the AngularJS front end. I migrated the on premise website hosting to Amazon S3 and CloudFront. This allowed us to retire the old Apache PHP servers and avoid major IT overhead for the company. In addition, performance was significantly improved with the new CDN. Continuing my efforts to modernize the tools used, I introduced eslint tools that ensured strict code standards. This identified and prevented several JavaScript coding errors.

- Added Sphinx compatible documentation to Python and Javascript.
- Documented development, build, and deploy processes for the entire stack.
- Added cache busting of the asset files to the build process.
- Converted PHP API a Python 3 API stack with test coverage for exposed surfaces.
- Designed MySQL database to include referential integrity and normalization.
- Corrected integrity issues and then migrated the existing database to the new design.
- Migrated the entire application from Linux VMs to AWS Cloud.
- Improved the AngularJS 1 application to conform to the current conventions in preparation for Angular 2.

## Software Development Engineer, Tervela, Inc.

Boston, MA - 2015-2016

My goal was to modernize the codebase by developing a method to safely upgrade outdated versions of MongodDB, Python, and other tools.

My first project was to upgrade MongodDB before the provider dropped support for the version in use. I conducted research and built tools to resolve differences between the versions. After upgrading the databases for non-production systems, I built tools to gather

and analyze logs from multiple servers to identify areas where problems were occurring and socialize them with my teammates.

Python upgrades are predicated on a solid testing system. I added automated testing into each of my projects. This included building a virtual environment where the Python code could be run locally using fixed versions of the packages to ensure reproducible results.

- Documented pylint standards.
- Built testing suite using py.test.
- Upgraded MongoDB from 2.4 to 2.6

# Senior Software Engineer, Happier, Inc.

Boston, MA - 2014-2015

As this small startup's primary developer I was responsible for the entire technology stack. I learned and documented the numerous processes used to make the stack robust and self sustaining.

Increased the python API performance by introducing RESTful principles for improved robustness. Which better supported the Android, iOS, and web applications.

I rapidly built new features for the web application and migrated the structure to follow the recommended best practices for modern modular designed websites.

- Converted the AngularJS single page app website to Flask/Jinja2 for better SEO.
- Created a custom CMS for internal content editing on the company website.
- Migrated backend to Heroku from EC2s saving thousands of dollars a month.
- Managed multiple MongoDB database version updates and configuration changes to performance resulting in query times being reduced to sub 50 milliseconds.
- Improved website rating in WebPageTest.org from D to A rating overall.

# Product Manager, SiteSpect, Inc.

Boston, MA - 2012-2014

As SiteSpect expanded I transitioned to the role of Product Manager where I increased product usability and adoption.

- Successfully revamped the user interface based on key user personas, resulting in an increase in user satisfaction and a boost in product adoption.
- Prioritized and managed the implementation of 4 major and 18 minor releases, including an alternate user interface that did not require Regular Expression knowledge to use.
- Trained Sales, Professional Services, and Platform Operations teams, leading to a reduction in support tickets and improved internal product knowledge.
- Developed and integrated an Online User's Guide, further enabling self-service and improving customer satisfaction.
- Led a team of 6 front-end developers using Agile methodology, ensuring on-time delivery within budget.

#### Advanced Solutions Engineer, SiteSpect, Inc.

Boston, MA — 2008-2012

As the first front-end engineer on the team, I supported dozens of customers by designing and implementing their A/B and multivariate experiments.

• Streamlined client support by designing and implementing best practices documentation for product usage.

- Mentored 5 ASEs and successfully trained dozens of clients, resulting in improved product adoption and reduced support tickets.
- Developed JavaScript libraries that improved in-page behavior tracking enabling data-driven decision making. This resulted in a new feature for the product.
- Created a comprehensive Regular Expressions guide and live training program, empowering non-developer client team members to leverage advanced testing features.
- Uncovered critical insights through custom log analysis scripts, optimizing multivariate testing campaigns and driving conversion rates.
- Championed quality assurance for product changes, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Proactively gathered and analyzed user feedback, bridging the gap between client needs and development priorities.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Worcester Polytechnic Institute**

Bachelor of Science Degree, Computer Science — 1998-2002

# **SKILLS**

- Python, Perl, Regular Expressions
- TypeScript, JavaScript, Angular
- Karma, Jasmine, Test Driven Development
- HTML5, Less, SASS, CSS, Bootstrap, Accessibility
- JSONAPI, OpenAPI Specification (Swagger)
- Linux, MacOS, Unix, Docker
- Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Firebase, Azure
- MySQL, sqlite, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Firestore
- Apache, Nginx, Flask, Jinja2, Tornado, Node, Terraform
- Bash, Awk, Grep, Sed, git, svn, GitHub
- pip, pipenv, virtualenv, npm

# **REFERENCES**

Available upon request.